MIKKEL LAURSEN

Lakewood, CO 80227

 $(804) \cdot 380 \cdot 7418 \diamond \text{mlaursen} 03@\text{gmail.com}$

SUMMARY

Full stack developer but mostly front end now with an interest and focus on web accessibility and creating reusable components in React. 3+ years experience writing React and SCSS, 3+ years experience with Java EE, Oracle/Microsoft SQL databases, and JSP/JSF pages.

EXPERIENCE

Four Winds Interactive

Jan 2018 - Present

Denver, CO

Senior Software Developer/Tech Lead

- · Leading the front end team for technical decisions and general mentoring
- · Implementing and maintaining an in-house component library to meet the UX and Design requirements
- · Developing and maintaining other shared libraries for the front end applications
- · Developing and maintaining our Library web application which allows users to upload/manage assets for our digital signs
- · Working closely with the UX and Design team to create user friendly web applications
- · Working closing with the QA automation team to ensure our apps are testable by Selenium and notifying them of any changes
- · Introduced Google analytics and implemented general analytics across all our web applications using Segment and Hotjar
- · Migrated our front end apps from a custom webpack build to a custom fork of create-react-app for consistent builds

Four Winds Interactive

June 2016 - Jan 2018

Software Developer

Denver, CO

- · Started the new CLOUD project to implement a mobile first/responsive web interface using React instead of Backbone.js
- · Introduced automated tests into the normal FE development pipeline using jest

TEDS, Inc.

May 2016 - June 2016

 $Senior\ Software\ Engineer$

Blacksburg, VA

- · Lead a team of 3 for a succession project written in React and Flux.
- · Developed and implemented an auto-generating javascript api from a Restful API's data/links.

TEDS, Inc.

March 2014 - June 2016

Software Engineer

Blacksburg, VA

- · Maintained and developed the main LMS system written in Java and Java Server Pages.
- · Maintained and redesigned the external recruitment site using Primefaces and Java Server Faces.
- · Developed and updated a C utility for upgrading databases and setting application privileges by amazing guesswork.
- · Updated and developed on the main project's ant build script.
- · Updated and maintained database update scripts.
- · Updated and maintained a java util to export job statuses into a csv file.
- · Developed a client facing restful web service for accessing and maintaining education.

- · Designed and implemented a compile time annotation processor to generate a standalone test page for the new web services.
- · Lead, designed, and developed a Java CRUD API framework for automagically generating GET, POST, PUT, DELETE request for any Database Entity during a work hackathon.
- · Implemented a new Dashboard application by optimizing and rewriting slow queries and built a new front end with React, Flux, bootstrap, and sass.
- · Maintained and developed the Dashboard application build process using gulp.
- · Rewrote a stalled 6 month project in 3 weeks using React and material design as inspiration.
- · Implementing a modularized code base by moving all our projects into a single repository and using maven to create the distributables.
- · Maintaining the front end build tools using webpack and npm.

CGI

Consultant

June 2013 - March 2014

Lebanon, VA

- · Front end development for an Oracle APEX website using jQuery.
- · Developed and documented tax forms in Java for the North Carolina Department of Revenue.

SMIPO January 2012 - January 2013

Directory of Information Technology

Radford, VA

- · Maintained and designed the Joomula website for keeping track of stock changes.
- · Migrated the Joomula website to WordPress.

Richmond Public Schools

June 2012 - August 2012

Intern Web Developer

Richmond, VA

- · Researched and implemented a DotNetNuke module for file sharing named DMX.
- · Implemented a script to rename files for human readability and then move the files to the correct location on the web server.
- · Developed a Java application to parse the sitemap data to alert the web team when a website has not been updated within a year's time so that it can be removed.

Richmond Public Schools

June 2011 - August 2011

Intern

Richmond, VA

- · Created a dataflow for IT fix-its using Microsoft SharePoint.
- · Created new forms on Microsoft InfoPath to replace the forms written in COBOL.
- · Assisted with web maintenance and migration to ASP.net.

EDUCATION

Radford University

June 2013

B.S. in Computer Science & Engineering with a Dual Concentration in Database and Software Engineering

Completed 3 Independent Studies and 3 team projects that delivered a product to real clients.

Overall GPA: 3.43

PROJECTS

React Material Design - react-md

January 2016 - Present

A material design UI components library using React and sass. A live demo of the documentation can be viewed at https://react-md.mlaursen.com

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer LanguagesJavaScript, Typescript, Java, bashDatabasesOracle, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL

Tools vim, git, yarn, npm

Other React, Redux, webpack, node